Having a ball… Wish you were here
Paris Is Burning is a documentary film directed by Jennie Livingston.
Where does voguing come from, and what, exactly, is throwing shade?
This landmark documentary provides a vibrant snapshot of the 1980s through the eyes of
New York City's African American and Latinx Harlem drag-ball scene.
Made over seven years, PARIS IS BURNING offers an intimate portrait of rival fashion "houses," from fierce contests for trophies
to house mothers offering sustenance in a world rampant with homophobia, transphobia, racism, AIDS, and poverty.
Featuring legendary voguers, drag queens, and trans women — including Willi
Ninja, Pepper LaBeija, Dorian Corey, and Venus Xtravaganza.
Self, played by Pepper LaBeija.
Self, played by Octavia St. Laurent.
Self, played by Venus Xtravaganza.
Self, played by Dorian Corey.
Self, played by Willi Ninja.
Self, played by Paris Dupree.
Paris Is Burning is a 1990 American documentary
film directed by Jennie Livingston.
Filmed in the mid-to-late 1980s, it chronicles the ball culture of New York City and the
African-American, Latino, gay and transgender communities involved in it.
Critics consider the film to be an invaluable documentary of the end of the “Golden Age” of New York City
Ballroom scene, and a thoughtful exploration of race, class, gender and sexuality in America.
In 2016, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being “culturally, historically or aesthetically significant”.
The film explores themes of new york city,
transvestism, aids, homophobia, drag queen.